<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Ernestas Poškus technical blog</title>
    <link>http://out13.com/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Ernestas Poškus technical blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 19:25:47 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://out13.com/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>/proc/meminfo - memory usage statistics</title>
      <link>http://out13.com/tools/proc-meminfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 19:25:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://out13.com/tools/proc-meminfo/</guid>
      <description>Reports statistics about memory usage on the system. Useful for inspecting more granular memory usage.
 Sample output below.
 $ cat /proc/meminfo MemTotal: 12189912 kB MemFree: 231992 kB MemAvailable: 4174992 kB Buffers: 430884 kB Cached: 4515856 kB SwapCached: 60 kB Active: 8019760 kB Inactive: 3120804 kB Active(anon): 6121448 kB Inactive(anon): 1099620 kB Active(file): 1898312 kB Inactive(file): 2021184 kB Unevictable: 3088 kB Mlocked: 3088 kB SwapTotal: 12467708 kB SwapFree: 12467352 kB Dirty: 1568 kB Writeback: 0 kB AnonPages: 6196916 kB Mapped: 1339276 kB Shmem: 1027248 kB Slab: 584576 kB SReclaimable: 349700 kB SUnreclaim: 234876 kB KernelStack: 20800 kB PageTables: 93864 kB NFS_Unstable: 0 kB Bounce: 0 kB WritebackTmp: 0 kB CommitLimit: 18562664 kB Committed_AS: 19186116 kB VmallocTotal: 34359738367 kB VmallocUsed: 0 kB VmallocChunk: 0 kB HardwareCorrupted: 0 kB AnonHugePages: 1019904 kB CmaTotal: 0 kB CmaFree: 0 kB HugePages_Total: 0 HugePages_Free: 0 HugePages_Rsvd: 0 HugePages_Surp: 0 Hugepagesize: 2048 kB DirectMap4k: 386324 kB DirectMap2M: 12083200 kB DirectMap1G: 0 kB  Interpreting each one  MemTotal: 12189912 kB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>slabtop - kernel slab cache information in real time</title>
      <link>http://out13.com/tools/slabtop-kernel-slab-cache-information-in-real-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 18:57:58 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://out13.com/tools/slabtop-kernel-slab-cache-information-in-real-time/</guid>
      <description>Displays detailed kernel slab cache information by aggregating /proc/slabinfo.
Tool shows a glimpse into kernel data structures.
 Sample output below.
 root@ow:~# slabtop -osc | head -n 20 Active / Total Objects (% used) : 4649227 / 4694474 (99.0%) Active / Total Slabs (% used) : 153429 / 153429 (100.0%) Active / Total Caches (% used) : 82 / 118 (69.5%) Active / Total Size (% used) : 1259115.61K / 1273939.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>