<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Garbage Collection on Ernestas Poškus.io</title>
    <link>http://out13.com/tags/garbage-collection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Garbage Collection on Ernestas Poškus.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 19:13:56 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://out13.com/tags/garbage-collection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>On the fly garbage collection</title>
      <link>http://out13.com/paper/on-the-fly-garbage-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 19:13:56 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://out13.com/paper/on-the-fly-garbage-collection/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In our abstract form of the problem, we consider a
directed graph of varying structure but with a fixed
number of nodes, in which each node has at most two
outgoing edges. More precisely, each node may have a
left-hand outgoing edge and may have a right-hand
outgoing edge, but either of them or both may be missing.
In this graph a fixed set of nodes exists, called &amp;ldquo;the
roots.&amp;rdquo; A node is called &amp;ldquo;reachable&amp;rdquo; if it is reachable
from at least one root via a directed path along the edges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subgraph consists of all reachable nodes and their interconnections is
called &amp;lsquo;the data structure&amp;rsquo;; nonreachable nodes that do not belong to the
data structure are called garbage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data structure can modified:
 - Redirecting an outgoing edge of a reachable node towards an already reachable one.
 - Redirecting an outgoing edge of a reachable node towards a not yet reachable one without outgoing edges.
 - Adding&amp;ndash;where an outgoing edge was missing an edge pointing from a reachable node towards an already reachable one.
 - Adding&amp;ndash;where an outgoing edge was missing an edge pointing from a reachable node towards a not yet reachable one without outgoing edges.
 - Removing an outgoing edge of a reachable node&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mutator: redirect an outgoing edge of reachable node towards an already reachable one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collector:
 - marking phase: mark all reachable nodes
 - appending phase: append all unmarked nodes to the free list and remove the markings from all marked nodes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Free list - collection of nodes that have been identified as garbage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>